Vitor Mello Senior Full Stack Engineer

vitor@vmello.com https://vmello.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/vitormv https://github.com/vitormv

Hello

Hi, my name is Vitor and I have 10+ years of experience as a Full Stack Engineer. I have very strong skills in javascript, ReactJs + Redux and responsive layouts. On the backend side I'm also highly proficient in PHP, Symfony and have some knowledge of infrastructure with Kubernetes, Docker and AWS. I love to break down complex scenarios, simplify processes and create simple solutions that help both the company and my fellow colleagues.

Education

Bachelor, Computer Systems Analysis

Centro de Estudos Superiores de Maceió, CESMAC 2005 - 2009

Skills

Javascript / ES6	(expert)
React / Redux / SSR	(expert)
php/symfony	(expert)
node.js	(intermediate)
html/css/sass	(expert)
Infrastructure	(intermediate)
UX	(intermediate)

Languages

English (fluent)
German (intermediate)
Portuguese (native)

Experience

Flixbus GmbH — Berlin, Germany Senior Full Stack Engineer

3+ years Feb 2016 - Present

Developed responsive components in React.js and Redux, React SSR, with highly performant javascript. Improved frontend team productivity by creating easy ways to mockup, fixture and test complex edge cases in the applications. Created an unified payment framework in php to speedup integration of 3rd-party payment APIs.

Tech Stack: javascript, reactjs, redux, jest, puppeteer, webpack, es6, babel, sass, node.js, php7, symfony, phpunit, mysql, redis, elasticsearch, amazon aws, kubernetes, docker, ab tests

Foodpanda GmbH — Berlin, Germany Senior Full Stack Engineer

2 years 7 months Jun 2013 - Dec 2015

Global food delivery company with shops in over 30 countries.

Tech Stack: javascript, php, mysql, html, sass, css, bootstrap, jquery, grunt, amazon sqs, elasticsearch, redis, git

Mobly — São Paulo, Brazil Lead Software Engineer Senior Full Stack Engineer 1 year 4 months Nov 2012 - May 2013

Feb 2012 - Oct 2012

Mobly is an e-commerce platform selling home furniture. This is the Brazilian branch of the european Home24, a venture started by Rocket Internet GmbH.

Tech Stack: javascript, php, mysql, html, sass, css, bootstrap, jquery, zend framework, yii, solr, memcache, git

Plus! Agência Digital — Maceió, Brazil Lead Full Stack Engineer Software Engineer

3 years 4 monthsJul 2010 - Dec 2011
Sep 2008 - Jun 2010

It's an award winning digital agency, creating a digital presence on the Web, Social Media, and also develops Intranet portals for clients.

Tech Stack: javascript, php, mysql, html, sass, css, bootstrap, jquery, zend framework, yii, solr, memcache, gits, elasticsearch, redis, git

Carango — Maceió, Brazil **Software Engineer**

1 year 3 monthsJul 2007 - Sep 2008

SEMARHP — Maceió, Brazil **Web Developer Intern**

1 year 6 months Mar 2007 - Aug 2008